Guide to the George Pierce Baker Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Pierce Baker papers
1878-1958
MS 51
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.25
(23 boxes, 1 folio)
The papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, printed matter, photographs, and memorabilia documenting George Pierce Baker's professional activities as head of the Department of Drama at Yale University. Correspondents include playwrights, critics, actors, and producers, who had been Baker's students. The papers detail Baker's activities as a lecturer, consultant to the film series Chronicles of America, chairman of the executive committee of the American Shakespeare Foundation, and author of a pageant for the American Society of Mechanical Engineers. Baker's interest in the Little Theatre movement, American Indian culture and art, the American Academy of Arts and Letters, and the Peterborough Memorial Pageant are also described.
Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from the Yale School of Drama, 1967 and 1970, and a gift from Elden T. Smith, 1978. Transferred from Drama Library, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is open for research, the original glass negative in Accession 2007-M-037 is restricted due to fragility. Plese consult the digital image (MADID #43744) or the print made from the original.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series and one addition: I. Correspondence, 1878-1936. II. Topical Files, 1890-1948.
Scope and Contents
The George Pierce Baker Papers consist of correspondence, manuscripts, printed material, photographs, and memorabilia, dating primarily from the eight years (1925-1933) during which George Pierce Baker served as the first head of the Department of Drama at Yale University. The papers document Baker's professional activities and affiliations rather than his teaching or administrative concerns at the fledgling drama school. Correspondents include playwrights, actors, producers, and drama critics, many of them former Baker students. Portions of the papers were received from the Yale School of Drama in 1967 and 1970 and from Elden T. Smith in 1978.
Series I is the larger of the two series and includes almost all correspondence in the papers. The material is filed either by personal name, by corporate name, or by topic. Name files include letters both by and about the designated person or institution, while topical correspondence files include letters from many people. Cross-references are provided when letters by an individual appear in several files. There are files for miscellaneous correspondence (folders 146-56), which include exchanges with friends and acquaintances of no more than two or three items. Files of miscellaneous requests (folders 157-63) include appeals for favors or advice from strangers. Topical correspondence files include materials concerning various club memberships (folders 33-36). There are also letters from producers seeking new plays or offering productions (folder 188), requests from journalists and others for information about Baker's activities (folder 201), and inquiries about articles or other publications from publishers (folders 202-205). Materials within topical correspondence files are arranged in alphabetical order. Series II includes Baker's writings, memorabilia, clippings, scrapbooks, photographs, and other material arranged by record type.
The papers include no files from Baker's tenure at Harvard University, but there is material for two pageants he produced during this period. In 1910 Baker wrote and directed the Peterborough Memorial Pageant, sponsored by the Edward MacDowell Association. Series I includes correspondence with the association, while in Series II there are clippings, photographs, memorabilia, and notes for the script (folder 300). In 1921 Baker created a pageant for the Plymouth tercentenary celebration. There is correspondence on the production in folders 32 and 186 in Series I, and Series II includes clippings and photographs of several scenes.
Salary, pension, budgets (folder 220), includes discussions between Everett Meeks and George Parmly Day concerning Yale's plans for a Department of Drama and the offer of the chairmanship to Baker. Several letters congratulate Baker on his pending move, and a few mention a controversy at Yale over the position of Edgar "Monty" Woolley.
Baker's reports on the Yale Drama Department are included in folders 303-304, but there is little else to document Baker's duties as chairman or his teaching responsibilities. Nevertheless, his influence as a teacher of drama is documented in the correspondence. Numerous former students write of their careers as playwrights, producers, actors, directors, and critics, often including clippings, promotional material, and scripts in their letters. Baker, in turn, offers encouragement and constructive criticism. Prominent among these correspondents is Eugene O'Neill, but the papers also include exchanges with Winthrop Ames, Frederick Ballard, Phillip Barry, S. N. Behrman, John Mason Brown, Hallie Flanagan, Sidney Howard, and Edward Sheldon. Both the O'Neill and Howard files discuss suits for plagiarism brought against these well-known playwrights. Lengthy exchanges with other former students including Joseph Curtin, Kenneth Raisbeck, James Daly, and Howard Phillips portray the challenges and difficulties facing those pursuing theatrical careers. They also attest to Baker's concern for the welfare of his students and document the sharp curtailment of theatrical activity and professional opportunities during the Depression.
The papers also document Baker's professional activities and affiliations between 1925 and 1933. Filed under the heading "Professional organizations" (folders 189-200) are materials representing Baker's participation in the American Academy of Arts and Letters and the National Academy of Social Sciences. Baker's lecturing is reflected in correspondence with tour managers (folders 115-129), while evidence of his professional writing is found in correspondence with publishers, co-author Henry Barrett Huntington (folder 99), and G. & C. Merriam Company, and in project files for the Pageant of America (folder 173) and the Chronicles of America film series (folders 23-31). Scripts and notes for several films are found in folders 301-302. For the fiftieth anniversary of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (1931), Baker produced a pageant titled "Control." Correspondence concerning the production, which used film footage as well as stage action, is found in the files for the Stevens Institute (folders 256-264); the script for "Control" is filed in Writings(folders 306-307). Other correspondence on pageants, including requests for assistance or offers of additional directorships, is found in the pageantry files (folders 174-175). Baker's support for the Little Theater movement can be seen in correspondence with his former students and also in exchanges with various local theater groups (folder 131), while his interest in Indian art and culture is reflected in correspondence with artist Oqwa Pi and others (folders 100 - 102).
Baker's knowledge of foreign theater, especially Czech, Irish, and British, is documented in correspondence with Czech friends (folder 49), Lady Gregory (folder 80), and Hallie Flanagan (folder 69). When the Shakespeare theater at Stratford-on-Avon burned in 1926, Baker, as chairman of the executive committee of the American Shakespeare Foundation, led the American campaign to raise a million dollars to rebuild the theater. The files (folders 224-247) include minutes of committee meetings and correspondence with Eleanor (Mrs. August) Belmont, Thomas W. Lamont, William H. Baldwin, Percy S. Bullen, Robert Duncan, and Archibald Flower. Printed material from the fund-raising campaign and plans and pictures of the winning design for the new theater are in Series II (folders 292-294).
Baker retired from Yale in 1933, and scattered throughout the files (and in folders 211 – 212) are congratulatory messages on the occasion. Correspondence with actress Dorothy Sands (folders 221-222) discusses plans for the retirement celebration, while clippings (folder 278) record the event. Letters of sympathy on Baker's death, two years later, are found in folders 276-277. Correspondents include Eugene O'Neill, Sidney Howard, and Frederick Ballard. Series II includes obituary clippings and retrospective evaluations of Baker's influence. The latter (folder 286) were written to Elden Smith by Baker's friends and students, when Smith was preparing his Ph.D. dissertation on Baker as a teacher of the theater arts (folder 299).
Biographical / Historical
George Pierce Baker was a professor of English at Harvard University (1888-1925) and first head of Yale University's Department of Drama (1925-1933). Numerous students from his courses in playwriting and his theatre workshop became prominent actors, playwrights, critics, and producers.
American drama; Authors and theater; Indian art -- North America; Little theater movement; Pageants; Peterborough (N.H.); Photoprints; Scripts; Dramatists; Educators; Ames, Winthrop, 1870-1937; Baker, George Pierce, 1866-1935; Ballard, Frederick, 1884-1957; Barry, Philip, 1896-1949; Bates, Esther Willard, 1884-; Behrman, S. N. (Samuel Nathaniel), 1893-1973; Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1879-1979; Brown, John Mason, 1900-1969; Curtin, Joseph; Daly, James Joseph, 1901-1945; Day, Frederic Lansing; Ehrensperger, Harold A. (Harold Adam), 1897-1973; Flanagan, Hallie, 1890-1969; Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940; Geddes, Norman Bel, 1893-1958; Goodnow, Edward P.; Granville-Barker, Harley, 1877-1946; Gregory, Lady, 1852-1932; Harris, George Edward, active 1925-1931; Houdini, Harry, 1874-1926; Howard, Sidney Coe, 1891-1939; Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1853-1937; Kauser, Alice, 1872-1945; Koch, Frederick H. (Frederick Henry), 1877-1944; Leigh, W. Colston; MacDowell, Marian, 1857-1956; Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Phillips, Howard; Pi, Oqwa; Pichel, Irving, 1891-1954; Pinero, Arthur Wing, 1855-1934; Raisbeck, Kenneth; Sands, Dorothy, 1893-1980; Sheldon, Edward, 1886-1946; Smith, Elden; Van Druten, John, 1901-1957; American Academy of Arts and Letters; American Shakespeare Foundation; American Society of Mechanical Engineers; Edward MacDowell Association; Yale School of Drama; Yale University Press; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. University theatre; Harris, G. Edward
- Correspondence, 1878-1936; Series I; 5.5 linear feet (13 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence is arranged in alphabetical order by personal and corporate name or by topic.
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters
    General note
    See: box 9, folders 189-198
  - American Shakespeare Foundation
    See: box 11, folders 224-247
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
    See: box 13, folders 256-264
  - Ames, Winthrop, 1926-1933, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Angell, James Rowland, 1929-1930, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anglin, Margaret, 1927-1928, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appia, Adolphe, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Archer, Charles, 1925, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Archibald, Mrs. Charles H., 1926-1927, 1929, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arliss, George, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bakeless, John, 1925, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ballard, Fred K., 1924-1930, 1932-1933, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Barry, Philip, 1923-1927, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bates, Esther W., 1925-1926, 1929, 1931-1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Behn, Harry, 1929-1932 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Behrman, Samuel Nathaniel, 1926-1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Belmont, Eleanor
    See: box 7, folders 146 See: box 11, folders 224-247
  - Brink, Roscoe, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brown, John Mason, 1925-1936 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Brown, Rollo W., 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Browne, Ellen V., 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Carlton, Henry Fisk, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Foundation, 1924-1926, 1928-1930, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Chadbourne, William M., 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    See also: box 2, folder 33
  - Chorpenning, Charlotte B., 1923, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Chronicles of America, 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 23-31)
  - Clifton, Chalmers D., 1920-1921, 1927, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Clubs, 1924-1933 (Box 2, Folder 33-36)
  - Commonwealth Fund, 1926, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Copeau, Jaques, 1925, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Cross, Wilbur, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    See also: box 2, folder 34 See also: box 10, folder 205 See also: box 10, folder 208 See also: box 13, folder 267 See also: box 17, folder 303
  - Crowley, Edward, 1926-1929, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Curtin, George and John, 1928, 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Curtin, Joseph, 1927-1933 (Box 2, Folder 42-48)
    See also: box 2, folder 41 See also: box 9, folder 184
  - Czechoslovakian friends, 1925-1929, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Daly, James J., 1924-1933 (Box 3, Folder 50-53)
  - Davit, Allan, 1924-1926, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Davis, Ruth Helen
    See: box 1, folder 6
  - Davison, Wilfred, 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Day, Frederick Lansing, 1926-1933 (Box 3, Folder 56-60)
  - George Parmly
    See: box 1, folder 20 See: box 10, folder 200 See: box 11, folder 220
  - Early correspondence, 1878-1906 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Ehrensperger, Harold Adam, 1925-1933 (Box 3, Folder 62-65)
  - Eisenstein, Sergei, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Eliot, Samuel, 1926-1927, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Feuillerat, Albert, 1925-1933 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Flanagan, Hallie Ferguson, 1924-1930, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Forbes-Robertson, Sir Johnston and Gertrude, 1915, 1925, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - 47 (Forty-seven) Workshop, 1924-1926, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Garland, Hamlin, 1925, 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    See also: box 9, folders 189-198
  - Geddes, Norman Bel, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Goodnow, Edward P., 1924-1934 (Box 4, Folder 74-78)
  - Granville-Barker, Harley, 1912, 1925-1926, 1928-1929,1932 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Gregory, Lady, 1925-1927, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Hagedorn, Hermann, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    See also: box 7, folder 134
  - Halman, Doris F., 1925-1927 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Hamilton, Clayton, 1927, 1929, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Hamilton, Edith
    See: box 8, folder 167
  - Hapgood, Norman and Elizabeth, 1930, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Harkness, Edward B., 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Harris, George Edward, 1925-1931 (Box 4, Folder 86-87)
  - Harris, William, 1925-1931, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Hartley, Roland, 1925-1926 (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Harvard University, 1927-1928, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Henderson, Archibald, 1926-1933 (Box 4, Folder 91-92)
  - Heyward, Dorothy and Dubose, 1924, 1926, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Hinkley, Eleanor, 1924, 1930, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Hodges, John W.K., 1932 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Houdini, Harry, 1925-1927 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Howard, Sidney Coe, 1925-1933 (Box 5, Folder 97-98)
  - Howe, Edith Coburn
    See: box 7, folder 139
  - Huntington, Henry Barrett, 1925-1928, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Indians, Americans, 1929-1933 (Box 5, Folder 100-102)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, 1925-1931 (Box 5, Folder 103-104)
  - Jones, Henry Arthur, 1924-1926, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Jones, Robert Edmund, undated (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Kauser, Alice, 1926-1933 (Box 5, Folder 107-108)
  - King, Laura, 1927, 1929-1930, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Knickerbocker, Edwin Van Berghen, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 110)
  - Knoblock, Edward and Gertrude, 1924-1932 (Box 5, Folder 111)
  - Koch, Frederick Henry, 1925-1936 (Box 5, Folder 112-113)
    See also: box 12, folder 239
  - Leckner, Myron C. and Reliance Holton, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Lectures, 1923-1933 (Box 6, Folder 115-129)
  - Lee, Sir Sidney, 1925-1926 (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Leigh, W. Colston
    See: box 6, folders 115-129
  - Little Theaters, 1925-1931 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    See also: box 5, folder 112-113 See also: box 9, folder 184
  - Lombard, Frank Alanson, 1925, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - MacDowell Association
    - General, 1924-1933 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Peterborough Pageant, 1910, 1927, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 134-135)
  - McFadden, Elizabeth A., 1925-1933 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - MacGowan, Kenneth, 1931, 1933, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    See also: box 8, folders 168-189
  - MacKaye, Percy, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - MacKenna, Kate, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Manley, William Ford, 1930-1932 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Marks, Jeannette, 1926-1930 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - Masaryk, John
    See: box 13, folder 254
  - Masefield, John, 1926, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Meeks, Everett Victor
    See: box 2, folder 34 See: box 9, folders 189-198 See: box 11, folder 220
  - Melrose, Alex, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Merriam, G. & C. Co., 1929-1933 (Box 7, Folder 144-145)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, A - M, 1890-1936 (Box 7, Folder 146-151)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, N - Y, unidentified, 1890-1936 (Box 8, Folder 152-156)
  - Miscellaneous requests, 1925-1934 (Box 8, Folder 157-163)
  - Morse, William Northrop, 1925, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - National Institute of Social Sciences
    See: box 10, folder 199
  - Nettleton, George, 1925-1927, 1929-1931, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Nicoll, Allardyce, 1928, 1931, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Oenslager, Donald, 1924, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1924-1933 (Box 8, Folder 168-169)
  - O'Neill bust, 1930-1934 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Osborne, Hubert, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Packare, Frederick C., Jr., 1925-1931 (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Pageant of America, 1925, 1927-1929 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Pageantry, 1915-1932 (Box 9, Folder 174-175)
  - Paulson, Arvid, 1932-1933 (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Peters, Rollo, 1930-1932 (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Peterson, Otto Peter, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 178)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1925-1935 (Box 9, Folder 179-180)
    See also: box 5, folder 105 See also: box 10, folder 200
  - Phillips, Howard, 1927-1931 (Box 9, Folder 181-183)
    See also: box 3, folders 56-60
  - Pi, Oqwa
    See: box 5, folders 100-102
  - Pichel, Irving, 1924-1931, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 184)
  - Pinero, Sir Arthur Wing, 1925-1926, 1931-1932 (Box 9, Folder 185)
  - Plymouth Tercentenary Pageant, 1915-1933 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Poel, William, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 187)
  - Producers, 1925-1934 (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - Professional organizations
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1925-1931 (Box 9, Folder 189-195)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1932-1933 (Box 10, Folder 196-198)
    - National Institute of Social Sciences, 1926-1933 (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - Miscellaneous, 1914-1933 (Box 10, Folder 200)
  - Publicity, 1925-1933 (Box 10, Folder 201)
  - Publishers, 1911-1933 (Box 10, Folder 202-205)
  - Radcliffe College, 1925-1930 (Box 10, Folder 206)
  - Raisbeck, Kenneth R., 1925-1933 (Box 10, Folder 207-209)
    See also: box 1, folder 10
  - Reniers, Percival, 1925-1932 (Box 11, Folder 210)
    See also: box 1, folders 23-31
  - Retirement, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 211-212)
  - Richardson, Harriette Taber, 1926-1930 (Box 11, Folder 213)
  - Roach, Alberta, 1931-1933 (Box 11, Folder 214)
  - Robinson, Donald Fay, 1926-1933 (Box 11, Folder 215-216)
  - Robinson, Edward Arlington
    See: box 8, folder 154
  - Robinson, Lennox, 1931-1932 (Box 11, Folder 217)
  - Robinson, Thomas P., 1924-1930 (Box 11, Folder 218)
  - Rouverol, Aurania, 1925-1929 (Box 11, Folder 219)
  - Salary, pension, budgets, 1924-1933 (Box 11, Folder 220)
  - Sands, Dorothy, 1925-1933 (Box 11, Folder 221-222)
  - Sayler, Oliver, 1924-1933 (Box 11, Folder 223)
  - Shakespeare Memorial Fund, 1926-1927 April 20 (Box 11, Folder 224-229)
  - Shakespeare Memorial Fund, 1927 April 21-1933 (Box 12, Folder 230-247)
  - Sheldon, Edward Brewster, 1925-1936 (Box 12, Folder 248)
  - Sikelianos, Eva, 1927-1929 (Box 12, Folder 249)
  - Simonson, Lee, 1927-1936 (Box 12, Folder 250)
  - Skinner, Otis and Maud, 1923-1930 (Box 12, Folder 251)
  - Smith, Boyd, 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 252)
  - Smyser, William, 1925-1932 (Box 12, Folder 253)
  - Stepanek, Orin, 1924-1932 (Box 13, Folder 254)
  - Stephenson, Nathaniel Wright
    See: box 1, folders 23-31
  - Stephenson, Paul, 1925-1930 (Box 13, Folder 255)
  - Stevens Institute Pageant, 1928-1931 (Box 13, Folder 256-264)
  - Strnad, Oskar, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 265)
  - Tanner-Green, Virginia, 1927-1929 (Box 13, Folder 266)
    See also: box 9, folders 174-175
  - Thorne, Doris
    See: box 13, folder 266
  - Ulmann, Doris, 1926 (Box 13, Folder 267)
  - Van Druten, John, 1927-1931 (Box 13, Folder 268)
  - Watson, Ernest Bradlee, 1925-1928 (Box 13, Folder 269)
  - Weinberger, Harry
    See: box 8, folders 168-169
  - Wertheim, Maurice, 1930-1933 (Box 13, Folder 270)
  - White, Albert and Edward, 1929-1931 (Box 13, Folder 271)
  - Wibbels, Henry, 1930-1933 (Box 13, Folder 272)
  - Woolley, Edgar, M., 1926 (Box 13, Folder 273)
  - Wright, Claud, 1925-1931 (Box 13, Folder 274)
  - Yale University Press
    See: box 1, folder 23-31 See: box 8, folder 173 See: box 10, folder 205
  - Young, Karl, 1925-1929 (Box 13, Folder 275)
  - Sympathy correspondence: to Mrs. George Pierce Baker, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 276-277)
- Topical Files, 1890-1948; Series II; 2.5 linear feet (4 boxes)
  The series is arranged in alphabetical order by record type.
  - Clippings
    - Retirement, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 278)
    - Harvard University, 1929-1937 (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Yale Theater, 1925-1933 (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Peterborough Memorial Pageant, 1910-1913 (Box 14, Folder 281-282)
    - Obituaries, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 283-284)
    - Miscellaneous, 1923-1933 (Box 14, Folder 285)
  - Correspondence: reminiscences of friends in letters to Elden Smith, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 286)
  - Diplomas
    See: box 18
  - Financial matters
    - Royalties, 1920-1933 (Box 14, Folder 287)
    - Taxes, 1924-1933 (Box 14, Folder 288-289)
  - Photographs, 1921-1932 (Box 14, Folder 290)
    See also: box 16, folder 296 See also: box 18
  - Printed material
    - Memorabilia, 1924-1935 (Box 15, Folder 291)
    - Shakespeare Fund, 1926-1930 (Box 15, Folder 292-294)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Yale retirement, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 295)
    - Peterborough Memorial Pageant, 1910 (Box 16, Folder 296)
  - Sheet music: by Edward MacDowell, 1890-1906 (Box 16, Folder 297-298)
  - Smith, Elden: thesis, "George Pierce Baker: A Critical Study of His Influence as a Teacher of Theatre Arts", 1947 (Box 17, Folder 299)
  - Writings, 1910, 1924-1932 (Box 17, Folder 300-308)
  - Oversize
    Folio
    - Diplomas, 1915, 1931 (Box 18)
    - Photographs, 1920, undated (Box 18)
- Additional material, 1900-1958; Accession 2007-M-037
  Separated Materials
  Student papers from the years that Baker taught at Harvard University (2 linear feet) were removed from the collection and returned to the Arts Library, Yale University.
  - Drama Department
    - Baker materials on the Yale and Harvard theatres, 1911-1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Craig, Edward Gordon, letters, 1912-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Yale University Theater (YUT) data, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Departmental expenses, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
    - Financial records
      - Audience fund, 1933-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Associates at the YUT, 1941-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Form letters, information, 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Clippings
      - 1900-1920s (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
      - Pertaining to Baker leaving Harvard, Circa 1924 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - 1930s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 47 Workshop
      - Applications to produce plays, 1920 April (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
      - Clippings, Circa 1912 (Box 2, Folder 6)